Register of the Stanislaw Mikolajczyk Papers, 1899-1966
Hoover Institution Archives
- GOVERNMENT SERVICE FILE, 1940-1946
  - Wicepremier [Deputy Prime Minister]. See also Premier
    - General
      - Transcripts of talks
        - General
          - Sikorski, Wladyslaw
            - Notes
              - 1942 (Folder 18)
              - 1943 (Folder 19)
        - "Notatki z rozmow" (Notes from talks). Bogomolov, Gavrilovic, Hodza, Heiret, Parel, Ripka, Slavik, Todorov, 1941 October-1942 October (Folder 20)
      - Anti-government press in Great Britain
        - Alarm, 1943 March-April (Folder 21)
        - Walka
          - 1941 (Folder 22)
          - 1942 (Folder 23)
          - 1943 (Folder 24)
      - Communist propaganda (Folder 25)
      - Kolo Slazakow - Post-war border, 1942 (Folder 26)
      - Peasant Group, London
        - General
          - 1942-1943
            - List (Folder 27)
            - Nos. 5-129 (Folder 28)
            - Nos. 130-284 (Folder 29)
            - Nos. 288-345 (Folder 30)
          - 1943-1944 (Folder 31)
        - Agricultural statistics for Eastern and Southern Europe, 1920s and 1940s (Folder 32)
        - International agrarian and political issues, 1941-1943 (Folder 33)
        - Peasant communities of Central and South-Eastern Europe. Program, 1941 (Folder 34)
      - Stronnictwo Jednosci, 1940-1942 (Folder 35)
- RADIO FREE EUROPE (Rozglosnia Polska Radia Wolna Europa), 1949-1965
  - General
    - Opening of Polish Section, 1952 (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - Recruitment of staff, 1949-1952 (Folder 2)
  - Commentaries
    - 1950
      - July-August (Folder 3)
      - September-October (Folder 4)
      - November-December (Folder 5)
    - 1951
      - January-February (Folder 6)
      - March-April (Folder 7)
      - May-June (Folder 8)
      - July-August (Folder 9)
      - September-October (Folder 10)
      - November-December (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - 1952
      - January-February (Folder 2)
      - March-April (Folder 3)
      - May-June (Folder 4)
      - July-August (Folder 5)
      - September-October (Folder 6)
      - November-December (Folder 7)
    - 1953
      - January-April (Box 67, Folder 1)
      - May-August (Folder 2)
      - September-December (Folder 3)
    - 1954 (Folder 4)
  - Correspondence
    - 1949 - National Committee for Free Europe (Folder 5)
    - 1950
      - General (Folder 6)
      - National Committee for Free Europe (Folder 7)
    - 1951
      - General
        - February-June (Folder 8)
        - July-December (Folder 9)
      - National Committee for Free Europe (Folder 10)
    - 1952
      - General
        - January-June (Folder 11)
        - July-December (Box 68, Folder 1)
      - Listeners in Poland (Folder 2)
    - 1953 (Folder 3)
    - 1955 (Folder 4)
    - 1956 (Folder 5)
    - 1957 (Folder 6)
    - 1959 (Folder 7)
    - 1962 (Folder 8)
    - 1964 (Folder 9)
  - Interviews
    - Stalin's death, 1953 (Folder 10)
    - Radio's status in Eastern Europe, 1958 (Folder 11)
  - Monitoring service transcripts
    - General, 1951-1955 (Folder 12)
    - Polish Monitoring Bulletin: Komunikat Nasluchu Radiowego, 1964 July (Folder 13)
    - Radio Warszawa 1,2,3
      - 1957
        - January-March (Folder 14)
        - April-June (Folder 15)
        - July-August (Folder 16)
        - September-December (Folder 17)
      - 1958 (Folder 18)
      - 1962
        - January-March (Folder 19)
        - April-June (Box 69, Folder 1)
      - 1963 (Folder 2)
      - 1965 - Elections
        - General (Folder 3)
        - Results (Folder 4)
    - Rozglosnia Kraj, 1956 (Folder 5)
    - USSR Home Service
      - 1950 July-December (Folder 6)
      - 1951
        - January-June (Folder 7)
        - July-December (Folder 8)
      - 1952 January-April (Folder 9)
  - Printed matter
    - Brochures (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Clippings
      - General (Folder 2)
      - Political developments in Poland, 1956 (Folder 3)
      - Radio Free Europe references to Poland
        - 1951-1952 (Folder 4)
        - 1959 (Folder 5)
    - Periodicals
      - General (Folder 6)
      - Biuletyn Rozglosni Kraj
        - 1955
          - General, September-December (Folder 7)
          - Appeal to the Poles abroad to return to the homeland (Folder 8)
        - 1956
          - January-June (Folder 9)
          - July-December (Folder 10)
      - Informacyjny Biuletyn Tygodniowy. Wiadomosci o Zyciu w Polsce
        - 1954 November-December (Box 71, Folder 1)
        - 1955
          - January-June (Folder 2)
          - August-December (Folder 3)
        - 1957 February-July (Folder 4)
        - 1958 February-March (Folder 5)
      - Inter-Catholic Press Agency, 1957:6,14 (Folder 6)
      - Komunikat Nasluchu Radiowego (Polish Monitoring Bulletin), 1956 November 29 (Folder 7)
      - RFE Daily Information Bulletin, 1954 January (Folder 8)
      - Wolna Europa, 1956 (Folder 9)
    - Press excerpts, 1954 (Folder 10)
  - Program transcripts
    - Hodza, Milan, 1964 (Folder 11)
    - Wilson, Woodrow-30th anniversary of death, 1954 (Folder 12)
    - Witos, Wincenty, 1951 (Folder 13)
    - World Freedom Fighters Day, Philadelphia, 1962 (Folder 14)
  - Reports
    - General
      - "Black Book"
        - Volume 1, 1952 (Box 72, Folder 1)
        - Volume 2, 1952 (Folder 2)
        - Volume 3, 1953
          - Part 1 (Folder 3)
          - Part 2 (Folder 4)
        - Volume 4
          - Part 1 (Folder 5)
          - Part 2 A (Folder 6)
          - Part 2 B (Folder 7)
      - Intelligence reports on political and social conditions in Poland
        - 1951 (Folder 8)
        - 1952 (Folder 9)
        - 1957 (Folder 10)
        - 1958 (Folder 11)
      - Presidential reports, 1950-1955, 1958 (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - American Motion Pictures for Freedom (Folder 2)
    - Communist governments in Eastern Europe members, 1964 (Folder 3)
    - Einsenhower's response to Bulganin's note, 1958 (Folder 4)
    - Government, law, and courts behind the Iron Curtain, 1955 (Folder 5)
    - Hungary - Events in 1953 (Folder 6)
    - Polish-East German relations, 1962 (Folder 7)
    - Soviet security organizations, 1961-1962 (Folder 8)
    - Swiatlo affair - Balloons to Poland, 1955 (Folder 9)
  - Speeches
    - 1951
      - General
        - General (Folder 10)
        - Drafts (Folder 11)
        - Typescripts (Folder 12)
      - Anti-peasant repressions in Poland (Folder 13)
      - Paderewski, Ignacy (Box 74, Folder 1)
      - Peasant Holiday (Swieto Ludowe) (Folder 2)
      - Petkov, Nikola (Folder 3)
      - Soviet system (Folder 4)
    - 1952
      - General (Folder 5)
      - Peasant Holiday (Swieto Ludowe) (Folder 6)
    - 1955
      - General
        - General (Folder 7)
        - Drafts. Includes talk on estimates of deportees to the Soviet Union in World War II (Folder 8)
      - Peasant Holiday (Swieto Ludowe) (Folder 9)
    - 1956 (Folder 10)
    - 1958 (Folder 11)
    - 1960 - Peasant Holiday (Folder 12)
    - 1961 - Peasant Holiday (Folder 13)
    - 1962 - Peasant Holiday (Folder 14)
    - 1963 - Peasant Holiday (Folder 15)
    - 1966 - Peasant Holiday (Folder 16)
- POLSKI NARODOWY KOMITET DEMOKRATYCZNY FILE (POLISH NATIONAL DEMOCRATIC COMMITTEE), 1950-1963
  - General
    - General (Box 74, Folder 17)
    - Eustachiewicz, Seweryn, Affair of, 1956 (Folder 18)
    - Executive Board
      - General
        - 1955 (Folder 19)
        - 1956 (Folder 20)
      - Members, 1962 (Folder 21)
  - Bulletins, 1954:1-5 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence
    - 1950
      - January-June (Folder 2)
      - July-December (Folder 3)
    - 1951 (Folder 4)
    - 1952 (Folder 5)
    - 1953 (Folder 6)
    - 1954 (Folder 7)
    - 1955
      - January-June (Folder 8)
      - July-December (Folder 9)
    - 1956 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - 1959 (Folder 2)
    - 1960 (Folder 3)
    - 1961 (Folder 4)
    - 1962 (Folder 5)
    - 1963 (Folder 6)
  - Declarations
    - Aims and Principles of Liberation of the Central and Eastern European Peoples, Independence Hall, Philadelphia, 1951 February 11
      - Correspondence
        - Polska Rada Polityczna (Folder 7)
        - Slavik, Juraj (Folder 8)
      - Description of ceremonies (Folder 9)
      - List of participants (Folder 10)
      - Press clippings (Folder 11)
      - Text of declaration (Folder 12)
    - Western Powers Conference toward the Soviet Union, 1959 March 16 (Folder 13)
  - Documents
    - 1955
      - List (Folder 14)
      - Nos. 1-9 (Folder 15)
      - Nos. 10-22 (Folder 16)
      - Nos. 23 (Folder 17)
      - Nos. 24-34 (Folder 18)
    - 1956
      - List (Folder 19)
      - Nos. 1-5 (Folder 20)
      - Nos. 6-10 (Folder 21)
      - Nos. 11-24 (Box 77, Folder 1)
      - Nos. 25-44. Includes materials on the Poznan Uprising (Folder 2)
      - Nos. 45-53 (Folder 3)
      - Nos. 54. Stanislaw Mikolajczyk's testimony on Poland and Hungary in the House of Representatives, 1957 November 17 (Folder 4)
      - Nos. 55-58. Polish-Soviet Treaty from 1956 November 18 (Folder 5)
    - 1957
      - List (Folder 6)
      - Nos. 1-21 (Folder 7)
      - Nos. 22-36 (Folder 8)
      - Nos. 37-43 (Folder 9)
    - 1958
      - List (Folder 10)
      - Nos. 1-11 (Folder 11)
      - Nos. 12-22 (Folder 12)
    - 1959
      - List (Folder 13)
      - Nos. 1-26 (Folder 14)
  - Membership applications and credentials, 1955-1956 (Box 78, Folder 1)
  - Memoranda
    - Foreign Ministers meeting, 1955 October 19 (Folder 2)
    - United Nations, 1953 (Folder 3)
  - Minutes of meetings
    - 1950 (Folder 4)
    - 1951 (Folder 5)
    - 1952 (Folder 6)
    - 1953 (Folder 7)
    - 1954 (Folder 8)
    - 1955 (Folder 9)
  - Press clippings
    - 1955 (Folder 10)
    - 1956 (Folder 11)
  - Session transcripts
    - First, 1951
      - General (Folder 12)
      - Communiqués (Folder 13)
      - Declarations (Folder 14)
      - List of members and member parties (Folder 15)
      - Memoranda (Folder 16)
      - Objectives and tasks (Folder 17)
      - Press releases (Folder 18)
      - Reports
        - General (Folder 19)
        - Activities (Folder 20)
      - Resolutions (Folder 21)
      - Speeches (Folder 22)
      - Statute (Folder 23)
    - Plenary, 1952
      - Correspondence (Folder 24)
      - Participants and members list (Folder 25)
      - Reports
        - General (Box 79, Folder 1)
        - Political conditions in Poland (Folder 2)
      - Resolutions (Folder 3)
      - Speeches (Folder 4)
      - Statute (Folder 5)
    - Second, 1953
      - General (Folder 6)
      - Announcements (Folder 7)
      - Correspondence
        - Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Folder 8)
        - Polish Socialist Party (Folder 9)
      - Participants and members lists (Folder 10)
      - Political program (Folder 11)
      - Protocols (Folder 12)
      - Reports on past activities (Folder 13)
      - Resolutions and appeals (Folder 14)
      - Speeches (Folder 15)
      - Statute (Folder 16)
    - Third, 1955
      - General (Folder 17)
      - Memoranda (Folder 18)
      - Participants list (Folder 19)
      - Reports
        - English (Folder 20)
        - Polish (Folder 21)
      - Resolutions (Folder 22)
      - Speeches (Folder 23)
  - Subject file - Unification Act, 1954
    - Émigré press clippings, 1951-1954 (Folder 24)
    - Text, entitled Akt zjednoczenia podpisany w dniu 14 marca 1954 roku w Londynie przez polskie niepodleglosciowe stronnictwa i ugrupowania polityczne (Folder 25)
- POROZUMIENIE STRONNICTW DEMOKRATYCZNYCH AND TYMCZASOWA RADA JEDNOSCI NARODOWEJ FILE (DEMOCRATIC ALLIANCE AND PROVISIONAL COUNCIL OF NATIONAL UNITY), 1927-1956
  - General
    - General
      - 1948 (Box 80, Folder 1)
      - 1949 (Folder 2)
    - Bulletin, 1962-1963 (Folder 3)
    - Declaration, 1948 (Folder 4)
    - Drafts, 1948 (Folder 5)
    - Notes
      - 1948 (Folder 6)
      - 1949 (Folder 7)
    - Press analysis
      - 1948
        - General (Folder 8)
        - Article by Stanislaw Mikolajczyk (Folder 9)
      - 1949 (Folder 10)
    - Reports
      - Political divisions, 1948 (Folder 11)
      - Unification
        - Efforts, 1954 (Folder 12)
        - Talks, 1947 (Folder 13)
        - Mission of General Kazimierz Sosnkowski, 1952-1954 (Folder 14)
  - Anticommunist activities. Open letter of Jan Choma-Ostaszewski to Poles abroad, 1956 (Folder 15)
  - Central East European Women's Federation (Folder 16)
  - Elections, 1962 (Folder 17)
  - Liga Niepodleglosci Polski, 1948-1951 (Folder 18)
  - Polska Partia Socjalistyczna, 1948 (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Polska Partia Socjalno-Demokratyczna, 1954-1956 (Folder 2)
  - Polski Ruch Wolnosciowy Niepodleglosc i Demokracja (Folder 3)
  - 1948-58
  - Polskie Stronnictwo Demokratyczne
    - General
      - 1942-1944 (Folder 4)
      - 1948-1953 (Folder 5)
    - Bulletin, 1948-1950 (Folder 6)
    - Program, 1939-1947 (Folder 7)
  - Rada Jednosci Narodowej
    - Brochures, 1954 (Folder 8)
    - Press clippings
      - 1952 (Folder 9)
      - 1954 (Folder 10)
      - 1955 (Folder 11)
      - 1956 (Folder 12)
  - Rada Narodowa, 1949-1951 (Folder 13)
  - "Sprawa Berg" (Berg affair), 1955-1956 (Folder 14)
  - Stronnictwo Narodowe
    - General
      - 1927-1938 (Folder 15)
      - 1941 (Folder 16)
      - 1942 (Folder 17)
      - 1943 (Folder 18)
      - 1944 (Folder 19)
      - 1945 (Folder 20)
      - 1947 (Folder 21)
      - 1948 (Folder 22)
      - 1950 (Folder 23)
      - 1951 (Box 82, Folder 1)
      - 1952 (Folder 2)
      - 1953 (Folder 3)
      - 1954-1956 (Folder 4)
    - Mysl Polska, 1941-1942 (Folder 5)
  - Stronnictwo Pracy
    - 1942-1945 (Folder 6)
    - 1946-1956 (Folder 7)
  - Tymczasowa Rada Jednosci Narodowej. Protocols, 1956-1958 (Folder 8)
  - Wolnosci i Niepodleglosc - Polish communist press
    - 1952 December (Folder 9)
    - 1953 January (Folder 10)
  - Zwiazek Ziem Wschodnich Rzeczypospolitej Polskiej, 1956 (Folder 11)
- POLSKA RADA POLITYCZNA FILE (POLISH POLITICAL COUNCIL), 1948-1953
  - 1948 (Box 82, Folder 12)
  - 1949 (Folder 13)
  - 1950
    - General (Folder 14)
    - Clippings (Folder 15)
    - Correspondence (Folder 16)
    - Publications. Inside Poland (Folder 17)
    - Session transcripts (Folder 18)
    - Statute (Folder 19)
  - 1951 (Folder 20)
  - 1952 (Folder 21)
  - 1953 (Folder 22)
- POLSKIE STRONNICTWO LUDOWE FILE (POLISH PEASANT PARTY), 1899-1966
  - General
    - General
      - 1939-1940 (Box 83, Folder 1)
      - 1941 (Folder 2)
      - 1943 (Folder 3)
      - 1944 (Folder 4)
    - Circulars, 1949-1951 (Folder 5)
    - Correspondence
      - General
        - 1939 (Folder 6)
        - 1940 (Folder 7)
        - 1941
          - January-June (Folder 8)
          - July-December (Folder 9)
        - 1942
          - January-June (Folder 10)
          - July-December (Folder 11)
        - 1943
          - January-June (Folder 12)
          - July-December (Folder 13)
        - 1944
          - January-June (Folder 14)
          - July-December (Folder 15)
        - 1945 January-June (Folder 16)
        - 1948 (Folder 17)
        - 1949
          - January-March (Box 84, Folder 1)
          - April-June (Folder 2)
          - July-September. Includes correspondence with Montini, Giovanni Battista (Folder 3)
          - October-December (Folder 4)
        - 1951-1952. Includes drawing of Joseph Stalin (Folder 5)
        - 1953
          - General
            - January-March (Folder 6)
            - April-June (Folder 7)
            - July-September (Folder 8)
            - October-December (Folder 9)
          - British Broadcasting Corporation (Folder 10)
          - Lane, Bliss (Folder 11)
          - United Nations (Folder 12)
          - United States. Congress (Folder 13)
          - United States. Department of State (Folder 14)
          - United States. Presidency (Folder 15)
          - Voice of America (Folder 16)
      - Executive Committee
        - 1947 (Box 85, Folder 1)
        - 1948
          - January-April (Folder 2)
          - May-August (Folder 3)
          - September-December (Folder 4)
        - 1949
          - January-February (Folder 5)
          - March-April (Folder 6)
          - May-June (Folder 7)
          - July-August (Folder 8)
          - September-October (Folder 9)
          - November-December (Folder 10)
        - 1950
          - January-February (Folder 11)
          - March-April (Folder 12)
          - May-June (Folder 13)
          - July-August (Folder 14)
          - September-October (Folder 15)
          - November-December (Folder 16)
        - 1951
          - January-February (Folder 17)
          - March-April (Folder 18)
          - May-June (Box 86, Folder 1)
          - July-August (Folder 2)
          - September-October (Folder 3)
          - November-December (Folder 4)
        - 1952
          - January (Folder 5)
          - February (Folder 6)
          - March (Folder 7)
          - April (Folder 8)
          - May (Folder 9)
          - June (Folder 10)
          - July-August (Folder 11)
          - September-October (Folder 12)
          - November-December (Folder 13)
        - 1953
          - January-February (Box 87, Folder 1)
          - March-April (Folder 2)
          - May-June (Folder 3)
          - July-August (Folder 4)
          - September-October (Folder 5)
          - November-December (Folder 6)
        - 1954
          - February-June (Folder 7)
          - July-December (Folder 8)
        - 1955
          - January-February (Folder 9)
          - March-April (Folder 10)
          - May-June (Folder 11)
          - July-December (Folder 12)
        - 1956
          - January-February
            - General (Box 88, Folder 1)
            - United States. Department of State and United States. President (Folder 2)
          - March (Folder 3)
          - April (Folder 4)
          - May (Folder 5)
          - June (Folder 6)
          - July (Folder 7)
          - August
            - General (Folder 8)
            - Lane, Bliss A. (Folder 9)
          - September-October (Folder 10)
          - November-December (Folder 11)
        - 1957
          - January-March (Folder 12)
          - April-June (Folder 13)
          - July-September (Box 89, Folder 1)
          - October-December (Folder 2)
        - 1958
          - January-April (Folder 3)
          - May-August (Folder 4)
          - September-December (Folder 5)
        - 1959
          - January-April (Folder 6)
          - May-August (Folder 7)
          - September-December (Folder 8)
        - 1960
          - January-April (Folder 9)
          - May-August (Folder 10)
          - September-December (Folder 11)
        - 1961
          - January-April (Folder 12)
          - May-August (Folder 13)
          - September-December (Folder 14)
        - 1962
          - January-March (Box 90, Folder 1)
          - April-June (Folder 2)
          - July-September (Folder 3)
          - October-December (Folder 4)
        - 1963
          - January-March (Folder 5)
          - April-June (Folder 6)
          - July-September (Folder 7)
          - October-December (Folder 8)
        - 1964
          - January-April (Folder 9)
          - May-August (Folder 10)
          - September-December (Folder 11)
        - 1965
          - January-April (Folder 12)
          - May-August (Folder 13)
          - September-December (Folder 14)
        - 1966
          - January-April (Folder 15)
          - May-August (Folder 16)
          - September-December (Folder 17)
      - Foreign branches
        - General
          - 1954 (Box 91, Folder 1)
          - 1965 (Folder 2)
        - Belgium
          - 1954-1955 (Folder 3)
          - 1957-1958 (Folder 4)
          - 1961 (Folder 5)
        - France
          - 1948 (Folder 6)
          - 1949 (Folder 7)
          - 1950 (Folder 8)
          - 1951 (Folder 9)
          - 1952 (Folder 10)
          - 1954
            - General (Folder 11)
            - Reports on activities in 1952-1953 (Folder 12)
          - 1955 (Folder 13)
          - 1957 (Folder 14)
          - 1958 (Folder 15)
          - 1959 (Folder 16)
          - 1960 (Folder 17)
          - 1961 (Folder 18)
          - 1962 (Folder 19)
          - 1963 (Folder 20)
        - Germany
          - 1954 (Box 92, Folder 1)
          - 1958 (Folder 2)
          - 1961 (Folder 3)
        - Great Britain
          - 1950
            - January-April (Folder 4)
            - May-August (Folder 5)
            - September-December (Folder 6)
          - 1951
            - January-April (Folder 7)
            - May-August (Folder 8)
            - September-December (Folder 9)
          - 1952 (Folder 10)
          - 1953 (Folder 11)
          - 1954
            - January-March (Folder 12)
            - October (Folder 13)
            - November (Folder 14)
            - December (Folder 15)
          - 1955 (Folder 16)
          - 1957 (Box 93, Folder 1)
          - 1960 (Folder 2)
          - 1961 (Folder 3)
          - 1962 (Folder 4)
        - Italy, 1953 (Folder 5)
        - Netherlands
          - 1954 (Folder 6)
          - 1955-1956 (Folder 7)
          - 1957-1958 (Folder 8)
          - 1959-1960 (Folder 9)
          - 1961 (Folder 10)
          - 1962-1963 (Folder 11)
        - Sweden
          - 1954 (Folder 12)
          - 1955 (Folder 13)
          - 1956-1957 (Folder 14)
          - 1960 (Folder 15)
        - Switzerland
          - 1945-1951 (Folder 16)
          - 1954-1955 (Folder 17)
          - 1957 (Folder 18)
          - 1960 (Folder 19)
        - Unites States, 1954 (Folder 20)
    - Publications
      - Biuletyn Europejskiej Rady PSL, Paris, no. 5, 1950 (Box 94, Folder 1)
      - Biuletyn Informacyjny Polskiego Stronnictwa Ludowego, Washington
        - 1947 (Folder 2)
        - 1948 (Folder 3)
        - 1949 (Folder 4)
        - 1950 (Folder 5)
        - 1952 (Folder 6)
        - 1953 (Folder 7)
        - 1959 (Folder 8)
        - 1963 (Folder 9)
      - Biuletyn Informacyjny PSL we Francji, Paris
        - 1949-1950 (Folder 10)
        - 1951-1952 (Folder 11)
      - Chlop i Panstwo, Warszawa
        - 1947 (Folder 12)
        - 1949 September (Folder 13)
      - Chlopski Sztandar, 1947 October-November (Folder 14)
      - Christian Social Association Bulletin, Warsaw
        - 1959-1960 (Folder 15)
        - 1962 (Folder 16)
      - Materialy Polityczne, no. 4, 1962 (Box 95, Folder 1)
      - Stronnictwo Ludowe "Wolnosc": Przeglad Polityczny, 1949-1955 (Folder 2)
      - Wyzwolenie Ludu, Salem, 1958 (Folder 3)
      - Zielony Sztandar
        - London, 1942 (Folder 4)
        - New York, 1952 (Folder 5)
    - Subject file
      - Post-war Polish agriculture
        - General, 1945 (Folder 6)
        - Hapon, Stanislaw, 1940 (Folder 7)
      - Underground peasant movement. Lecture by Stanislaw Grabski, 1944 (Folder 8)
  - Conferences
    - Chatham House Conference, London, 1942-1943
      - General
        - Index (Folder 9)
        - Nos. 1-89 (Folder 10)
        - Nos. 90-199 (Folder 11)
        - Nos. 200-299 (Folder 12)
        - Nos. 300-381 (Folder 13)
      - Eastern European agriculture, Reconstruction of
        - Index (Folder 14)
        - Nos. 1-57 (Folder 15)
    - European Agriculture Conference, British Association for the Advancement of Science, 1942 March 20-21
      - General
        - Index (Folder 16)
        - Nos. 2-74 (Folder 17)
      - Post-War European Agriculture, Russel, J. E. (Folder 18)
  - Congresses
    - General
      - First
        - 1946 January 19-21, Warsaw
          - General (Box 96, Folder 1)
          - List of leaders (Folder 2)
          - Program and statute (Folder 3)
          - Resolutions (Folder 4)
          - Thesis (Folder 5)
        - 1955 March 5-7, Paris
          - General (Folder 6)
          - Communiqués (Folder 7)
          - Correspondence
            - January (Folder 8)
            - February (Folder 9)
            - March (Folder 10)
            - April-June (Folder 11)
            - July-September (Folder 12)
            - October (Folder 13)